https://www.offitkurman.com/../privacy-policy/

MenuAboutServicesAttorneysResourcesCareersLocationsContact
Search for:
The Better Way To Protect Your Data
This Privacy Policy was published on October 5, 2018, and last updated on October 5, 2018. We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time.We Take Our Privacy Seriously.This privacy policy contains information about Offit Kurman, P.A. and how and why we collect, store, use and share your personal data. It also explains your rights concerning your personal data and how to contact us or supervisory authorities in the event you have a complaint.This website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.Controller, Processor, and Data Privacy OfficerThis privacy notice is issued on behalf of Offit Kurman, P.A.  The words "we", "us", "our", or “Offit Kurman” in this privacy notice refer to Offit Kurman, P.A. which is responsible for processing your data and is the controller and responsible party for this website.Our Data Privacy Officer is Robert Skinner, who can be reached at 301-575-0300 or via email at _rskinner@offitkurman.com, or regular mail at 8171 Maple Lawn Boulevard, Suite 200, Maple Lawn, MD 20759, USA.We hope that we can resolve any concern you may raise about this website or our use of your information.   If you live or work in the European Union or European Economic Area, the General Data Protection Regulation gives you right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority where you work, normally live, or where any alleged violation of data protection laws occurred.  We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns ourselves first, and will endeavor to address all issues to your reasonable satisfaction if you contact us in the first instance.Please inform us of changes to your Personal DataTo assure that any personal data we hold about you is accurate and current, please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.Third-party links will take you to third party sites for which we are not responsibleThis website may include links to third-party websites and third-party applications. We do not control these third-party sites.  If you click on a link and leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of any linked site for that site’s privacy policy. Data We Will Collect About You?Personal Data We Will CollectContact data such as your name, address and telephone number, email addressInformation to enable us to check and verify your identity, e.g. your date of birthElectronic contact details, e.g. your email address and mobile phone numberInformation relating to the matter in which you are seeking our advice or representationYour financial details so far as relevant to your instructions, e.g. the source of your funds if you are instructing representation and engagementTechnical Data including internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.Usage Data includes information about how you use our website, products and services.Personal Data We May Collect Depending on How You Have Instructed UsYour employment status and details including salary and benefits, e.g. if you instruct us on matter related to your employment or in which your employment status or income is relevantYour employment records including, where relevant, records relating to sickness and attendance, performance, disciplinary, conduct and grievances (including relevant special category personal data), e.g. if you instruct us on matter related to your employment or in which your employment records are relevantYour racial or ethnic origin, gender and sexual orientation, religious or similar beliefs, e.g. if you instruct us on discrimination issuesMarketing and Communications Data includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.Information to enable us to undertake a credit or other financial checks on youProfile Data includes your username and password, your interests, preferences and feedback. We also collect, use and share aggregated data such as statistical or demographic data. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. How Is Your Personal Data Collected?We use different methods to collect data from and about you, including: Direct Interactions CollapseWe collect most of this information directly from you.  This includes personal data you provide when you request our services, subscribe to our publications, request marketing material to be sent to you, or give us feedback. Automated technologies or interactions ExpandAs you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, [server logs] and other similar technologies. Third Parties or Publicly Available Sources ExpandWe may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources.  This could include analytics providers such as Google and our social media pages, including Twitter and LinkedIn. How and Why We Use Personal Data?We will only use your personal data when the law allows us and we have a proper reason to do so, such as:to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations;for the performance of our professional services for you or to take steps at your request before commencing our services;for our legitimate business or commercial interests or those of a third party and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.; orwhere you have given consent.Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party)Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.The table below explains the purpose for which we use or process your personal data and our reasons for doing so:Our Purpose in Using Your Personal DataOur reasons for Using or Processing the Personal DataType of DataTo provide legal services to you.For the performance of performing our professional services or to take steps at your request before performing the services.(a) identity
(b) contact
(c) profile
(d) marketing and communicationsConducting checks to identify our clients and verify their identity
Other processing necessary to comply with professional, legal and regulatory obligations that apply to our businessTo comply with our legal and regulatory obligations.(a) identity
(b) contact
(c) profileOperational reasons, such as improving efficiencyFor our legitimate interests or those of a third-party, i.e. to make sure we are following our own internal procedures so we can deliver the best service to you(a) identity
(b) contact
(c) profile
(d) usage
(e) marketing and communications
(f) technicalEnsuring the confidentiality of commercially sensitive informationFor our legitimate interests or those of a third-party, i.e. to protect our intellectual property and other commercially valuable information
To comply with our legal and regulatory obligations(a) identity
(b) contact
(c) profile
(d) usage
(e) marketing and communications
(f) technicalTo deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you.Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of clients for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)(a) identity
(b) contact
(c) profile
(d) usage
(e) marketing and communications
(f) technical There may be other specific types of special data which we will only process with your explicit consent.Our Promotional OffersWe may use your personal data to send you updates (by email, text message, telephone or regular mail) about legal developments that might be of interest to you and/or information about our services, including offers, promotions or new services.  We have a legitimate interest in processing your personal data for promotional purposes (see above “How and why we use your personal data”). This means we do not usually need your consent to send you promotional communications.We will always treat your personal data with the utmost respect and never share it with other organizations for marketing purposes, except that we, on occasion, may share information with third party partners for the purposes of hosting events.  Outside of hosting events, we will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company outside Offit Kurman.Opt-Out RightsYou have the right to opt out of receiving promotional communications at any time by:contacting us by emailusing the ‘unsubscribe’ link in emailsCookiesWe use cookies to personalize content and ads, to provide social media features, and to analyze our traffic. You consent to our cookies if you continue to use this website.  You also can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see our policy on cookies.Change of purpose We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it.  If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.How long your personal data will be keptWe will keep your personal data after we have finished advising or acting for you. We will do so for one of these reasons:to respond to any questions, complaints or claims made by you or on your behalf;to show that we treated you fairly;to keep records required by law. We will not retain your data for longer than necessary for the purposes set out in this policy. When it is no longer necessary to retain your personal data, we will delete it.  In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Your Legal Rights below for further information.We may anonymize your personal data so that it can no longer be associated with you for research or statistical purposes.  If we do that, we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.Where your personal data is heldInformation may be held at our offices and those of our third-party agencies, service providers, representatives, and sometimes agents as described above (see “Our Promotional Offers” above).We are based in the United States or America and many of our third-party agencies, service providers, representatives, and agents are based in the United States of America.  If you are from the European Union or European Economic Area, processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the European Union or European Economic Area.  We ensure protection is afforded to your data by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:We use providers based in the USA which are part of the Privacy Shield, requiring them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US. For further details, see European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield. If we are using non-USA providers, we will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details, see European Commission: Adequacy of the protection of personal data in non-EU countries.On rare occasions where we may use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries.Please contact us {NEED LINK} if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EU or EEA.Offit Kurman’s data securityWe have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorized manner.  In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know and who are subject to a duty of confidentiality.Where we are legally required to do so, we will notify you and any applicable regulator of a data breach, if it does occur despite our measures to prevent it.Your legal rightsUnder certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data, including the right to:Request access to your personal data, so you can receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and check that we are lawfully processing it.Request transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party.Request correction of the personal data that we hold, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.Request erasure of your personal data for any of several reasons, including where there is no valid reason for us continuing to process it or we have improperly processed it.  We will comply with your request, subject to any specific legal requirements.Object to processing of your personal data where the processing has been used for direct marketing.  In addition, you may object if the processing impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms, subject to compelling legitimate grounds which may in some circumstances override your rights and freedoms.Request suspension of our processing of your personal data for a reasonable period while the parties consider if other reasons for objecting may apply.Where we are relying on your consent to process your personal data, you may withdraw your consent at any time. But if you do, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you.You, of course, have the right to complain to us or your supervisory authority where you work, normally live, or where any alleged violation of data protection laws occurred.We will respond promptly to any exercise of your legal rights, but we may be delayed in certain circumstances to verify your identity.If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us. {NEED LINK}
New York & New JerseyNew York City (Manhattan), NY Metro Park, NJ Pennsylvania Harrisburg, PA Philadelphia (Center City), PA Plymouth Meeting, PA DelawareWilmington, DE MarylandBaltimore, MD Columbia, MD Frederick, MD Bethesda, MD Washington DC & VirginiaTysons Corner, VA Washington DC North CarolinaCharlotte, NC©2020 Offit Kurman, Attorneys At Law. All Rights Reserved | Disclaimers | Login
Privacy Policy | Cookie Policy
Skip to content
Open toolbar
Accessibility Tools
Increase Text
Decrease Text
Grayscale
High Contrast
